Guide to the Lloyd A. Fallers Papers 1937-1977
University of Chicago Library
Fallers, Lloyd A. Papers
1937-1977
28 linear feet (56 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Fallers, Lloyd A. Papers comprise 28 linear feet of materials including personal and professional correspondence, field notes and research materials, course materials, and manuscripts concerning other professional associations and projects in which he was engaged. The papers contain materials generated by Fallers while pursuing research into colonialism and independence in East Africa, modernization in Turkey, and more general topics of social stratification and status. The collection also includes field materials collected by Margaret Chave Fallers.
Information on Use
Access
Series X, Microfilms, is currently restricted due to the need for special equipment. Series XI, Letters of Reference, is restricted and not open for research until 2024.
Biographical Note
Lloyd Ashton Fallers, Jr., generally called Tom, was born in Nebraska City, Nebraska, on August 29, 1925, the son of Lloyd A. Fallers and Fannie Lincoln. He graduated from East High School, Salt Lake City, Utah, in 1943. After spending a year at the University of Utah (1943-1944) and a year at Deep Springs College (1944-1945) Fallers came to the University of Chicago in the fall of 1945 and completed his Ph.B. degree in 1946.
Arriving at the University of Chicago, Fallers had intended to study medicine but found that his interests gravitated towards the study of society. Pursuing these growing interests he began to study anthropology. Fallers conducted anthropological field work under the direction of Sol Tax for four months in Iowa during 1948, and this research formed the basis of his master's thesis on "The Role of Factionalism in Fox Acculturation." He was awarded an A.M. degree in anthropology in 1949.
In 1949 Fallers married Margaret Chave who was also a graduate student teaching in the College. In autumn 1949 Fallers attended the London School of Economics on a Fulbright Scholarship to study with Audrey Richards, Raymond Firth, Daryll Forde, and Edmund Leach. Richards had recruited Fallers for study in Africa on a visit to the University of Chicago. On Richards' recommendation as director of the East African Institute of Social Research, Fallers was awarded a Colonial Social Science Research Council fellowship to help her establish the Institute in Kampala, British Protectorate of Uganda. In 1950 Fallers left for East Africa and, as a fellow of the East African Institute, conducted a study of the Busoga. He returned to the University of Chicago in 1952. During the course of the following year, Fallers, acting as an instructor in the Department of Anthropology, worked on his dissertation with Robert Redfield, Fred Eggan, and Lloyd Warner. Fallers was awarded a Ph.D. degree in 1953.
In his dissertation, entitled "Bantu Bureaucracy: A Study of Role Conflict and Institutional Change in the Soga Political System," Fallers investigated the role of the headman in village life and the ways in which change in the wider colonial political system had influenced this role. In doing so, he addressed how the indigenous Busoga political institutions and the British administrative structure had come to form a single institutional complex.
Later Fallers expanded his thesis, and published it in revised form under the title Bantu Bureaucracy: A Study of Integration and Conflict in the Political System of an East African People (1956). The material which Fallers collected, somewhat incidentally while he was doing research, about Busoga law and
courts was presented much later in his Law without Precedent: Legal Ideas in Action in Courts of Colonial Busoga (1969).
In 1953 Fallers went to Princeton for one year as a lecturer in anthropology. The following year he returned to Uganda. As Uganda was preparing for self rule, Fallers acted as the Senior Research Officer at the East African Institute before being appointed Richards' successor as Director of the Institute at the beginning of 1956. There Fallers worked with, among others, J. La Fontaine, Priscilla Reining, Aidan Southall, Martin Southwold, Derrick Stenning, and J. W. Tyler. It was during this period that Fallers conducted research into the leadership and political institutions of Buganda (1954-1957). Fallers' work formed the core of his edited volume entitled The King's Men: Leadership and Status in Buganda on the Eve of Independence (1964), which was part of a larger project on the study of leadership financed by the Carnegie Corporation.
Fallers, returning to the United States in 1957, was appointed Assistant Professor and subsequently Associate Professor at the University of California, Berkeley. He spent 1958-1959 at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences in Palo Alto in the company of Clifford Geertz, Fred Eggan, David Apter, Meyer Fortes, Raymond Firth, and Morris Janowitz. In 1960 Fallers returned to the University of Chicago as an Associate Professor of Anthropology. Fallers was appointed Professor at the beginning of 1964 and for the year 1967-1968 was the first recipient of the Henry Schultz Rotating Research Professorship in the Social Sciences. In 1970 Fallers was given a joint appointment to the departments of anthropology and sociology, and in 1972 he was named the A. A. Michelson Distinguished Service Professor.
On his arrival at the University in 1960 Fallers played a central role in founding the Committee for the Comparative Study of New Nations, which was established to encourage the comparative analysis of the social, political, administrative, cultural, and economic changes associated with the development of new states in Africa and Asia. On July 1, 1970, Fallers succeeded Clifford Geertz as the chairman of the committee. Fallers was also active in the Committee on African Studies and in the Center for Middle Eastern Studies. The various interests Fallers developed while participating in the academic life of the University were used, by him, to thematically draw together a collection of previously published essays in Inequality: Social Stratification Reconsidered (1973). These interests also formed the basis of his edited volume Immigrants and Associations (1967).
Throughout his career Fallers was actively engaged in a large number of projects which extended beyond the immediate University community. In 1958 Fallers participated in the Ford Foundation's Review of African Studies Programs in the United States. Then in 1961 Fallers was appointed Associate Editor for Anthropology for the International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, a project in which he was actively engaged throughout the decade. During 1962-1963 Fallers, Kwamena Bentsi-Enchill, Denis Cowen, and Allison Dunham formed the commission on land tenure for the government of Basutoland which was funded by the Ford Foundation. This was a team of University of Chicago professors who were invited to make recommendations to the government regarding land tenure and land law. In recognition of his wide scholarly contributions Fallers was elected to the American Academy of the Arts and Sciences in 1972.
While developing his interests in the problems of modernization Fallers began, in the early 1960s, to conduct preparatory research on Turkey and in 1964 conducted field research in Konya, Turkey. In 1968 Fallers, accompanied by his wife, went to Edremit, Turkey, for one year to analyze the function of a small community in the operation of the larger national society. He returned to Edremit in 1971, but this stint of research was cut short when he had to return to Chicago after fracturing his elbow. Earlier Fallers had been successfully treated for a brain tumor. Now medical examinations revealed his cancer had reappeared. Fallers' condition deteriorated, and he died on July 4, 1974.
Fallers' last book, The Social Anthropology of the Modern Nation-State (1974), was based on the Lewis Henry Morgan Lectures which he gave at the University of Rochester in April 1971. In these lectures he compared the situations of East Africa and Turkey, crystallizing much of what he had learned about modernization and social change. This book was published posthumously.
Scope Note
The Fallers, Lloyd A. Papers cover the years 1937 to 1977 and are arranged into eleven series. They include: Series I, Biographical Materials, Series II, Correspondence, Series III, Course Materials, Series IV, Manuscripts by Fallers, Series V, Manuscripts by Others, Series VI, Africa Research Materials, Series VII, Turkey Research Materials, Series VIII, International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, Series IX, Margaret Chave Fallers Papers, Series X, Microfilms and Series XI, Letters of Reference.
The collection includes personal and professional correspondence, field notes and research materials, course materials, and manuscripts concerning other professional associations and projects in which he was engaged. Some of the correspondence includes Peter Benedict, Clifford Geertz, Marion Levy, Morris Janowitz, Michael Meeker, Audrey Richards and Aidan Southall as well as administrative correspondence concerning the Department of Anthropology, the Committee for the Comparative Study of New Nations, and the Committee for African Studies with which Fallers was involved.
The collection also contains materials generated by Fallers while pursuing research into colonialism and independence in East Africa, modernization in Turkey, and more general topics of social stratification and status. A substantial amount of information on Fallers' research for the East Africa Institute of Social Research can be found in Series VI. The collection includes editorial correspondence and manuscripts from when Fallers served as Associate Editor for Anthropology for the Institute Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences. It also contains field materials collected by Margaret Chave Fallers.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Fallers, Lloyd A.; Benedict, Peter, 1938-; Chave, Margaret E.; Geertz, Clifford; Levy, Marion J. (Marion Joseph), 1918-; Janowitz, Morris; Richards, Audrey Isabel, 1899-; Southall, Aidan William; International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences; University of Chicago.Dept. of Anthropology; University of Chicago.Committee for the Comparative Study of New Nations; Baustoland; Lesotho; Buganda; Bugosa (Uganda); Marshall Islands; Turkey; Leadership; Developing countries; Anthropologists
INVENTORY
- Series I: Biographical Materials
  Series 1, Biographical Materials (Box 1), contains Lloyd A. Fallers' curriculum vitae, a diary, awards he received, an appointment calendar, a number of his reprints, and administrative materials concerning his appointments at the University of California, Berkeley, from 1957 to 1960.
  - Curriculum vitae, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Engagement calendar, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Reprints, 1952-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - University of California, Berkeley, appointments, salary, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Awards, 1948-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Correspondence
  Series II, Correspondence (Boxes 1 to 17), has been arranged alphabetically and consists of Fallers' professional and personal correspondence between the years 1955 and 1974. Included in this series is substantial correspondence with Peter Benedict, Clifford Geertz, Marion Levy, Morris and Gayle Janowitz, Michael Meeker, Audrey Richards, and Aidan Southall, Fallers' successor as Director of the East African Institute of Social Research. The Fallers Papers do not include correspondence covering the years when Fallers was in Africa except where some pieces of correspondence are included in Series VI, African Research Materials. Series II also contains Fallers' administrative correspondence and papers concerning the Department of Anthropology, Committee for the Comparative Study of New Nations, and Committee for African Studies at the University of Chicago.
  - A, general, 1958-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Adams, Robert M., 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - African Studies Association, 1958-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ainsworth, Mary, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Airforce Space Digest, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Albert, Ethel M., 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1965-1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alele, Grace, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Allen, Raymond B., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Academy of the Political and Social Science, 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Anthropological Association, 1960-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Anthropological Association, "Models for the Study of Kinship Structure, "1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Political Science Review, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Sociological Review, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Sociologist, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anastaplo, George, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Antoun, Richard T., 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Apter, David E., 1958-1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Apthorpe, Raymond, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Arbuz, George, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Archives Europeennes de Sociologie, 1962-1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Association of Social Anthropologists, correspondence, newsletters, 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Aswad, Barbara C., 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Australian National University, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - B, general, 1958-1973 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Balikci, A., 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Barber, Bernard, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Barnes, John A., 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Barth, Fredrick, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bar-Yosef, R., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Basehart, Harry W., 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Baum, Robert D., 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Beadle, George W., 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Beals, Ralph L., 1958-1966 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Beattie, John H. M., 1958-1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Bendix, Reinhard, 1958-1974 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Benedict, Peter, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Bennigsen, Alexandre, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bialor, Perry, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bianchi, Robert R., 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Binder, Leonard, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Black, Cyril E., 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1962-1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bohannan, Paul J., 1958-1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Book orders, 1958-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Braidwood, Robert J., 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Brauer, Jerald C., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - British Journal of Sociology, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Brown, Bernard O., 1966-1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bruckner, D. J. R., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bryant, William P., 1959-1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Buchanan, Roland L., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Buckman, Miriam E., 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1961-1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Bulliet, Richard W., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Burhoe, Ralph W., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Butler, Jeffery, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Byewaso, George W., 1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - C, general, 1958-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Caplow, Theodore, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cartland, G. B., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chicago Council on Foreign Relations, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chodak, Szymon, 1963-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Christensen, James, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Church Society for College Work, Faculty Summer School in Theology and Religion, Episcopal Theological School, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cohen, Andrew, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cohn, Bernard S., 1963-1971 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Coleman, James S., 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Collier, Jane F., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Conta, Erika von, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cosgrove, Tom, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Crabb, David, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Cronin, Constance, 1959-1973 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Crocker, J. Christopher, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - D, general, 1957-1973 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Danforth, Sandra, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - de Bunsen, Bernard, 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Dictionnaire d'Anthropologie Juridique, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Dirks, Edward J., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dolci, Danilo, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Doob, Leonard W., 1957-1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Douglas, H. Toni, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Dubisch, Jill, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - E, general, 1957-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Eggan, Fred, 1958-1968 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Eisenstadt, Shmuel N., 1962-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Elkan, Walter, 1958-1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - el-Zein, Abdul Hamid, 1968-1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1959-1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Erzioni, Amitai, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - F, general, 1958-1973 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Fabian, Johannes, 1965-1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Fearn, Hugh, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Firth, Raymond, 1959-1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ford Foundation, 1959-1965 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Forde, Daryll, 1958-1961 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Foreign Area Fellowship Program, 1963-1966 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Foreign Service Institute, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Foster, Philip J., 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Friedl, Erika, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Friedland, William H., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - G, general, 1958-1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Geertz, Clifford, 1965-1974 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Gluckman, Max, 1957-1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Goldman Construction Company, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Goldschmidt, Walter, 1957-1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Goldthorpe, John E., 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Good, Charles M., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Goodenough, Ward H., 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Goody, Jack, 1960-1971 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Greeley, Andrew M., 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Gulliver, Philip, 1958-1964 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Gutkind, Peter C. W., 1958-1966 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - H, general, 1957-1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Hall, Clara S., 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Hammond, Peter B., 1963 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Hanson, Allan, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Harper and Row Publishers, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Harris, Alfred, 1966-1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hemphill, Marie, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Herskovits, Melville J., 1958-1962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hilsman, Roger, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Hinnant, John, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Hoben, Allan, 1966-1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Hodgson, Marshall S., 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Hopkins, Nicholas S., 1965-1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Horvath, T., 1971 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Howe, C. H. Walter, 1952-1962 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Hunt, Eva, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Hunter, Grace, 1958-1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - I, general, 1958-1974 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Institute of International Education, 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - International African Institute, 1958-1964 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - International Catholic Auxiliaries, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - J, general, 1958-1972 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Janowitz, Morris and Gayle, 1962-1971 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Janzen, John M., 1962-1968 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Johnson, D. Gale, 1961-1970 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Johnston, Bruce F., 1959-1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Jones, William O., 1959-1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Journal of the American Academy of Religion, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - K, general, 1958-1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Kahan, Arcadius, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Kamoga, Fred K., 1958-1968 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Kaplan, Irving, 1961-1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Karpat, Kemal H., 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Keil, Charles, 1964-1972 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Kennedy, John F., 1962 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Kerr, Clark, 1957-1967 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Khare, Ravindra S., 1964-1973 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
  - Khuri, Fuad, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Kiray, Mübeccel, 1965-1971 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Klein, Martin A., 1967 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Kolars, John F., 1963-1966 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Kroeber, Alfred L., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - L, general, 1958-1974 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Levine, Donald N., 1961-1970 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - LeVine, Robert A., 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Levi, Edward H., 1964-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Levy, Marion J., Jr., 1958-1972 (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
  - Lilienthal, Philip E., 1960-1973 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lipset, Seymour M., 1958-1967 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Lofchie, Michael F., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Löffler, Reinhold, 1965-1971 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Low, D. Anthony, 1958-1971 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lystad, Robert A., 1961 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - M, general, 1958-1973 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
  - Mair, Lucy, 1957-1961 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Makerere University College, 1959-1970 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Mansur-Cosar, Fatma, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Maquet, Jacques, 1958-1964 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Mardin, Serif, 1967-1973 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Mathur, Prad B., 1972 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - McCoy, Joseph A., 1968 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - McQuown, Norman, 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mediterranean Social Anthropological and Sociological Conference, Nicosia, September 7-12, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Meeker, Michael E., 1964-1972 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
  - Middleton, John, 1958-1969 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Mikva, Abner, 1968-1971 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Miner, Horace, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Molnos, Angela, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Montgomery, John D., 1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Moore, Wilbert E., 1958-1963 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Morin, Alexander, 1965-1973 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Morrill, Warren T., 1960 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Morrison, Charles, 1966-1971 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Murphy, Robert, 1959-1963 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Musoke, Simon B. K., 1958-1967 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Mutual of New York, 1958-1961 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - N, general, 1958-1973 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Nader, Laura, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Legal Defense Fund, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - National Science Foundation, 1961-1973 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Nekam, Alexander, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - New York Times, 1961-1970 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Nolte, Richard H., 1961 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - O, general, 1958-1972 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Okpala, Charles E. N., n.d. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Olakanpo, O., 1970 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Ottenberg, Simon and Phoebe, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Owusu, Maxwell K., 1966-1971 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Oxford University Press, 1960-1970 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - P, general, 1959-1973 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Pandey, Triloki Nath, 1965-1973 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Papanek, Hanna, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Parsons, Talcott, 1965-1971 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Paynes, Denis, 1960-1963 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Peacock, James L., 1966-1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Pease, Phyllis, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Peristiany, John, 1969-1974 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Peters, Emrys L., 1967-1971 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Pifer, Alan, 1958-1967 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Pitt-Rivers, Julian, 1961-1972 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Plotnicov, Leonard, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Polk, William R., 1965-1970 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Powdermaker, Hortense, 1960-1961 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Prather, Emelie O., 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Pratt, R. Cranford, 1957-1973 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Pritchett, C. Herman, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Q, general, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - R, general, 1958-1973 (Box 12, Folder 13)